Kevin L. Miller, Ph.D.

klmille@gmail.com | (310) 562-4572 | Los Angeles, CA 90230

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/kevin-miller-phd-1b197986/ | GitHub: github.com/Koldenblue

Portfolio: kevin-miller-react-portfolio.herokuapp.com

SUMMARY

Full-Stack Web Developer with a Ph.D. in chemistry from the University of California, Los Angeles (UCLA). Education in full-stack development from UCLA. Experienced problem-solver and scientific researcher. Values ethics, integrity, and good business sense, having spent years as a business manager and scientist. Extensive teaching experience lends itself to public speaking, leadership, and teamwork skills. Top aim is to contribute to a team while continuously improving coding skills. Seeks to improve the lives of teammates and clients, whether that be in the real world or the digital world.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- JavaScript/HTML/CSS used as main coding languages
- Emphasis on MERN stack technologies (MongoDB, Express, React, and Node.js) for front-end and back-end design, database management, routing, and client-server communication
- SQL database work, through MySQL and the Sequelize Object-Relational Mapper (ORM)
- MongoDB along with Mongoose or mongo.js, for non-relational database management
- Coding techniques include object-oriented programming, asynchronous function handling, responsive web design, and code testing
- AJAX calls for retrieving data from and integrating APIs
- ¡Query, Bootstrap, Handlebars, and other established libraries for streamlining web development
- Research of libraries for example, Moment is or Node Package Manager packages such as Inquirer
- Ability to quickly learn additional programming languages and techniques for example, Python and C/C++ programming accomplished through self-study and professional certification

PROJECTS

Inform and React | https://inform-react.herokuapp.com/ | github.com/Koldenblue/Inform-and-React

- Executed lead back-end scripting for a small team of coders. Programmed all routes and led database design. Performed code review, React component design, and overall project design.
- Designed and coded a React-driven app. Programmed AJAX calls to API databases, database storage with MongoDB, and user authentication routes, with a goal of providing voter information

Express Bartender

https://team-express-bartender.herokuapp.com | github.com/Koldenblue/Express-Bartender

- Led a small team in database design and storage of user information. Reviewed team code and contributed assistance to front-end website design.
- Programmed an SQL database of drink recipes to cater to authenticated users. Coded ability to add, modify, and delete user recipes. Acquired initial database information using API calls.

Color Rippler | https://color-rippler.herokuapp.com/ | github.com/Koldenblue/color-rippler

- A personally-designed and coded ongoing art project that takes advantage of the React framework to efficiently render a large number of interactive components.
- Combines front-end design, algorithms, and webpage routing for dynamic interactivity

EMPLOYMENT

Twinwood, Inc.:

Property Manager and Accountant

October 2013 - Present

- Rigorous documentation and coordination of construction projects, with spending in the hundreds of thousands, benefited both tenants and the company through substantial property improvement
- Meticulous business analytics helped achieve a yearly company growth rate of 3.6% of net worth

Praxair:

Lab Technician and Analytical Scientist

October 2014 - February 2015

• Carefully managed lab testing allowed for a fast throughput of dozens of highly pure gasses daily

University of California, Los Angeles:

Researcher / Teaching Assistant

Sept. 2007 - July 2013

- Intense scientific research led to seven published research papers
- Personal mentoring of two undergraduates helped them publish their own scientific papers
- Chemistry research was awarded Ralph and Charlene Bauer Award, as well as two separate fellowship awards
- Close supervision of hundreds of undergraduate students in both labs and discussion sections, during teaching of over a dozen college-level chemistry discussion courses

EDUCATION

Coding Bootcamp - UCLA Extension
CS50 Professional Certificate - HarvardX Online
Ph.D., Chemistry - University of California, Los Angeles
B.S., Chemistry - University of California, Irvine

October 2020

to be completed November 2020

Dec. 2014

June 2007